（火神(かがみ)）うりゃ！
The final tip-off!
（リコ）ファイナル ティップオフ
（火神）勝ちてぇ
黒子(くろこ)と… みんなと！
I want to win with Kuroko and the guys!
（火神）とりゃ
（ホイッスル）
（葉山(はやま)）なっ…
（赤司(あかし)）面白い
Interesting.
ゾーンか
The Zone, huh?
Isn't It the Best?
What? Again?
（実渕(みぶち)）
なっ… まさか また!?
（根武谷(ねぶや)）うおぉぉぉ！
火神君
Kagami-kun...
（伊月(いづき)）すごい…
Amazing.
やはりゾーンに入ったときの
攻撃力は桁が違う
His offensive power is incredible
when he's in the Zone,
けど…
but...
Isn't this bad?
（諏佐(すさ)）
これって やばくねぇか？
The Zone consumes a lot of stamina, right?
ゾーンって体力の消耗も
半端ねぇんだろ
Will he last until the end of the game?
最後まで持つのかよ？
（青峰(あおみね)）持つわけねぇだろ
Of course not.
（青峰）風呂の浴槽にお湯を
目いっぱい張ったとすんじゃん
Suppose you fill a bathtub with hot water.
What? A tub?
は？ 風呂？
（青峰）ゾーンに入ったときは
その栓を抜いたようなもんだ
Entering the Zone is like pulling the plug.
The water disappears before your eyes.
みるみるうちに お湯は減る
Simple enough, but does he think I'm stupid?
丁寧で分かりやすいけど—
オレ バカだと思われてんのか？
（今吉(いまよし)）
いや 気に入られとんちゃう？
No, maybe he likes you.
何か手を打たねぇと—
If they don't do something,
he'll be running on empty before halftime.
最後までどころか—
前半でガス欠だぜ
We can't even touch him on defense!
（根武谷）ディフェンスも
手がつけられねぇ！
Rakuzan
Seirin
（小金井(こがねい)）すごい
洛山(らくざん)を０点に抑えてる
Amazing.
He's keeping Rakuzan at zero points.
No one even comes close to Kagami.
（土田(つちだ)）火神の独壇場だ
（リコ）水戸部(みとべ)君
Mitobe-kun, get ready to sub in.
（リコ）交代準備よろしく！
（降旗(ふりはた)）カントク？
Coach?
I'd rather keep going than try to stop him.
下手にブレーキかけるぐらいなら
このまま行くわよ！
ただし スタミナ切れを
起こさないためにも—
But Kagami-kun needs to focus on offense
so he doesn't run out of stamina.
火神君にはオフェンスに
専念してもらうわ
Kuroko-kun, you're out.
（リコ）黒子君 交代
（黒子）え？
What?
（伊月）黒子を水戸部(みとべ)に？
You're subbing Kuroko for Mitobe?
（木吉(きよし)）なるほど
I see.
Overall, Mitobe's stronger
on defense than Kuroko.
ディフェンスなら 総合的に
水戸部のほうが上だからな
I was ready to give everything I had...
（黒子）ボク 結構やる気全開で
出てったんですけど
Don't let it get you down.
（小金井）そう 落ち込むなって
（観客１）
なんだ あいつ もう交代？
They're subbing him out already?
（観客２）
もっとプレー見たかったぁ
I wanted to see him play more!
The fans want to see you, too.
（小金井）
観客も期待してくれてるし—
すぐ また出番あるさ
You'll be out there in no time.
（黒子）はい
Yeah.
てことで火神
オマエはオフェンスに専念だ
Kagami, focus on offense.
We'll handle things back
here while you charge ahead!
後ろはオレたちに任せて
ガンガン行け！
Got it!
うっす！
Rakuzan
Seirin
Coach, shouldn't we call a time out?
（アシスタントコーチ）監督
一度タイムアウトを取ったほうが
（白金(しろがね)）必要ない
There's no need.
くそっ 火神め
Damn. Is Kagami stronger than
Midorima when he's in the Zone?
ゾーンに入ったときは
緑間(みどりま)以上じゃねぇか
手がつけられないわね
We can't touch him.
We'll keep offense as is.
（赤司）
オフェンスはこのままでいく
On defense, Kotaro, we'll switch marks.
（赤司）ディフェンスは小太郎
（葉山）ん？
（赤司）マークチェンジだ
（葉山）はっ！
（伊月）なっ！
（日向(ひゅうが)）あっ！
Akashi...
赤司！
少し調子に乗りすぎているようだね
火神大我(たいが)
You're getting carried away,
Kagami Taiga.
I knew it.
やはり 来たわね
Kagami-kun...
火神君…
両チーム 絶対的エースの衝突
It's a clash of the aces.
The results will affect the flow of the game.
ここの結果は
この先の流れに直結するで
What should we do?
（伊月）どうする!?
それでも火神でいくか—
Do we stick with Kagami
or attack with just us?
オレたちだけで攻めるか
The latter option is lower risk, but...
リスクが低いのは後者だが…
Give me the ball!
（火神）くれっ！
ここで赤司を
逆にぶっ倒せば—
If I can crush Akashi
now, we'll take control!
一気に流れに乗れる
Kagami...
（伊月）火神っ！
It still sends shivers down my spine.
相変わらず背筋凍るで
But it's now or never.
けど 持ってもうたら 待ったなしや
The Zone versus Emperor Eye!
ゾーン 対 エンペラーアイ
（若松(わかまつ)）火神の速さが
エンペラーアイを超えた！
Kagami's speed beat Emperor Eye?!
Kagami!
（誠凛(せいりん)部員たち）
うぉー！ 火神っ！
I can do it!
（火神）行ける
一気にとどめを刺してやる
I'll finish this now!
Go, Meteor Jam!
（小金井）
行けーっ！ メテオジャム！
（赤司）エンペラーアイを超えた？
Beat Emperor Eye?
Don't underestimate me.
見くびってもらっては困るな
わざと抜かせたんだ
I let you pass me.
Unbelievable.
（リコ）なんてヤツなの！
Kagami-kun took a larger step
forward to avoid Akashi-kun.
火神君は赤司君のカットを
かわすために—
１歩目の踏み込みが
大きくなっていた
その分 ドライブが
外に膨らんで—
His drive went wide, taking him
slightly farther from the hoop.
わずかにゴールまでの距離が
遠くなってしまった
（アレックス）
しかもメテオジャムは—
And he can't use his Meteor Jam
when the defense is too close.
ディフェンスと ある程度
距離がないと使えない
（花宮(はなみや)）
５番と８番のヘルプが遅れた—
No. 5 and No. 8 were slow to help.
It was the perfect chance.
絶好のシチュエーション
それさえも わな！
But even that was a trap.
I thought they'd use a flashy
trick to stop Kagami's Zone.
（今吉）ゾーンの火神を
止めるために—
どんだけ派手な
仕掛け打つかと思えば—
最初の一手で詰ますとか—
But stopping him with their
first move was superhuman.
人間業ちゃうで
It just goes to show...
心底思い知ったわ
Akashi isn't unbeatable
because he has Emperor Eye.
赤司はエンペラーアイを持つから
無敵なんちゃう
赤司がエンペラーアイを持つから
無敵なんや
He's unbeatable because of how he uses it.
止めるぞ １本！
Let's stop their shot!
（火神）くそぉ オレのミスだ
That was my mistake!
I know I had other options!
あの場面 他にも
選択肢はあったはずなのに！
Idiot. He's losing focus.
バカが 雑念が出てきたな
（伊月）しまった スクリーン！
Crap, a screen!
Switch!
（伊月）スイッチ！
（紫原(むらさきばら)）へえ
Aka-chin's rushing to end a game for once.
（紫原）赤ちんにしては珍しく
一気に片つけにきたね
If they lose this, he'll leave the Zone.
ここで負けたらゾーンが切れる
But I hope that's all.
だけなら まだいいが—
100パーセントの力を発揮して—
If full power doesn't work against him,
it could throw him off completely.
それが通用しないとなりゃ—
反動で一気に絶不調もありえるぜ
But Kagami-kun beat Kise-kun's
Emperor Eye once before.
（リコ）けど 火神君は
黄瀬(きせ)君のエンペラーアイを—
一度こらえてる！
Now that he's in the Zone, maybe...
ゾーンに入ってる 今なら
あるいは…！
（赤司）
あまり 僕を いらつかせるな
Don't make me so angry.
How dare you compare a fake to the original.
フェイクとオリジナル
比べられることすら不快だ
Your head is too high.
頭(ず)が高いぞ
（若松）赤司ペネトレイト！
Akashi's inside!
（土田）イーグルスピア！
Eagle Spear!
（伊月）このタイミングでもダメか
Not even this timing worked!
Crap!
（日向）しまった！
No, you don't!
させん！
If they don't stop him now, they're screwed.
（今吉）ここで止めんと
マジでやばいで
エース対決で完敗した流れからの
失点なんぞ—
The points they'll lose
from the momentum lost
in the ace showdown are bad enough.
最悪もええとこや
火神 １人の問題やない
It wasn't Kagami's mistake alone.
It will be engraved into all their heads.
誠凛全員の頭に
刷り込まれることになる
“赤司には何をやっても
勝てない”
"No matter what we do,
Akashi is unbeatable."
うおぉぉぉ！
（木吉）くそ！
Damn!
What?
（木吉）水戸部！
Mitobe!
Nice, Mitobe!
ナイス 水戸部
Yeah, Rin-nii!
（水戸部の兄弟）
やったぁー！ 凛(りん)兄！
He got me!
もう やられた
No worries, Leo!
どんまい レオ姉
（赤司）少し詰めが甘かったか
I was naive.
It wasn't as though no one was on him.
ノーマークだったわけではない
が それ以上に…
But more importantly...
Mitobe-kun's fired up, too!
水戸部君も
気合入ってるってことよ！
Everyone on our team is today!
こっちは 今日—
そこらへん
全員もれなく満タンよ！
Let's go! Counterattack!
いくぞ 反撃だ！
（火神）オフェンス 攻めねぇと
We need to go hard on offense...
But how?
けど どうやって？
Can I beat Akashi?
オレは赤司に勝てるのか？
Mitobe-senpai...
水戸部… 先輩
He says, "Don't worry about it!"
“ドンマイ 気にすんな”
だってさ！！
Even I understood that!
（火神）今のは
オレでも分かるんスけど!?
雰囲気で！
はぁ… よっしゃ
Yeah!
これってゾーンが解けた？
Is he out of the Zone?
ああ いつもどおりにな
Yeah, he's back to normal.
体力も まだ残ってる
He still has some strength.
It was probably the best
possible way to leave the Zone.
解け方としては
ひとまず最高じゃねーの？
You've got some good teammates, Taiga...
（アレックス）いいチームメートを
持ったな タイガ！
オフェンス 取り戻すぞ！
Offense! Let's get them back!
Yeah!
（選手たち）おう！
（リコ）ウチの流れは途切れてない
We haven't lost momentum completely.
火神君のゾーン抜きでも
十分やれてる
Even without Kagami-kun's Zone,
we stand a fighting chance.
So...
なら…
（観客１）出た！
誠凛のスーパーシックスマン！
There he is!
Seirin's super sixth man!
（観客２）行けー！
Go!
（根武谷のおなら）
（根武谷）おっと
Whoops.
（実渕）なんで出るのよ
こんなときに！
Why are you doing that now?
おっと ごめんなさいね
Sorry.
いえ
It's okay.
Huh?
（降旗）黒子をよけた？
He avoided Kuroko?
（観客１）行けー！ 11番
Go, No. 11!
（降旗）観客にも
The fans see him, too...
That can't be right.
おかしいよな？
だって 誰にも気付かれないのが
普通のはずなのに！
Normally nobody notices him.
うん よかった！
Great. Akashi got you,
but you haven't given up.
赤司にやられても
まだ諦めてないっ
ん… 当たりめぇだ 何言ってる!?
What? Of course not!
What are you talking about?
ん？ だってさぁ—
I mean, come on...
戦意なくして
しょぼくれたヤツに—
It's no fun playing guys who
have lost their will to fight.
やり返しても—
面白くないじゃんよ
You passed us twice.
もう２回も抜かれたもんね
I'll pass you five times.
５回は抜くよ
（火神）ん？ ５!?
倍返しで４回とかじゃねぇの？
Five? Wouldn't people normally double it?
How did he get that number?
計算方法が よく分からん
Well, whatever.
まあ いいや
I'll pass you so many times,
you can't keep up!
何度でも抜いて
返しきれなくしてやらぁ！
（伊月）火神！
Kagami!
There are others who feel
"wild" like Taiga!
（アレックス）
タイガ以外にもいたか
この気配 “野生”
（火神）こいつ！
This guy...
くそっ！
（観客１）
出たぁ！ 11番のミラクルパス！
There it is! No. 11's miracle pass!
触ってたのか
You touched the ball?
まあね けど 問題は
そこじゃないわよ 順平ちゃん
Yeah.
But that's not the problem, Junpei-chan.
（日向）順平ちゃん!?
Junpei-chan?
No, you don't!
（火神）行かすかぁ！
行くよ ４本だ！
Here we go!
Four!
（火神）
マジで 消えたように見える！
It looks like it disappeared!
He made the shot! Hayama's Lightning Dribble!
（観客）決まった！
葉山 電光石火！
Let's go, Kuroko! Get on offense!
（日向）行くぞ 黒子 オフェンスだ
洛山から点を取るには
全員の力を合わせなきゃ ダメだ
We'll need to work together
to score against Rakuzan!
Pass the ball around!
パス回してくれよ！
Something's not right.
（降旗）やっぱり変だ
Kuroko hasn't been able
to shake the defenders.
さっきから もう 黒子は
ほとんどディフェンスを外せてない
まさか 黒子の影の薄さが
なくなってる!?
Is Kuroko's lack of presence weakening?
Coach, um...
カントク！ あの…
ルーズボール 取って！
The ball's free! Get it!
テツ君のパスが破られた？
They intercepted Tetsu-kun's pass?
いや…
No...
（青峰）テツにシュートを
教えたときの違和感
So this is why I felt uneasy
about teaching Tetsu to shoot.
あれは つまり こういうことかよ
Damn it. How did you...
くそっ 一体 どうやって…
何も 見えてたから取ったの
それだけよ
I didn't do anything.
I just blocked what I saw.
What he saw?
（日向）見えてた？
So when he caught up to my three...
じゃあ さっきスリーに
追いつかれたのも…
…てことは まさか！
Could it be?
I can't bear to watch this folly.
（赤司）見るに堪えない愚行だよ
How could you abandon your greatest strength?
唯一最大の長所を自ら手放すとは
（赤司）オマエが中学時代
今のスタイルに行きついたあと—
Once you reached your current
style in middle school,
I helped you work on pass variations,
僕はパスのバリエーションを
増やすことはさせても—
シュートやドリブルは
身につけさせなかった
but wouldn't let you shoot or dribble.
Do you know why?
なぜだか 分かるかい？
それをすれば—
Because I knew it would make
you lose your lack of presence.
いずれ影の薄さが失われることが
分かっていたからだ
The Vanishing Drive, the Phantom Shot.
バニシングドライブ
ファントムシュート
How could a player who uses such
flashy moves not stand out?
そんな派手な技を使う選手が
目立たないはずないだろう
The last nail in the coffin was your
buzzer beater in the semifinals.
さらに決定打は
準決勝のブザービーター
When you learned to shine dimly,
you ceased being a shadow.
なまじ光ることを
覚えたばかりに—
オマエは
もはや影にもなれなくなった
No longer the Phantom Sixth Man,
幻のシックスマンで
なくなったオマエでは—
you're worth less than the average player.
すでに並の選手の価値もない
And you didn't notice until now.
こうなることに 今まで
気付けなかったなんて…
You disappoint me, Tetsuya.
失望したよ テツヤ
（伊月）くそっ 普通の
フェイント程度にしかなってない
Damn it.
They're hardly better than normal feints.
（伊月）あっ
（日向）伊月！
Izuki!
少し甘かったか
I was too gentle.
黒子君
Kuroko-kun.
（花宮）まあ 当然 下げるだろ
They have to sub him out.
使えなくなった切り札を
出しとく意味はねぇ
There's no point in keeping
a useless trump card around.
He might not come back.
もう 出番はないかもな
黒子君！
そっちじゃなくて こっち こっち！
Kuroko-kun!
Not over there. Come here.
Don't give up.
諦めないで！
また すぐ出てもらうわよ
You'll be back out there soon.
What?
What? They're sending him out again?
なっ また出すのかよ!?
Sorry, Kuroko-kun,
for sending you back like this.
（リコ）すまないわね 黒子君
こんなふうにコートに戻すなんて
（黒子）いいえ 逆です
No, I'm sorry.
いってきます
Here I go.
はぁ？ 何考えてやがる？
What are they thinking?
Just over three minutes
left in the first quarter.
（リコ）第１クオーター
残り３分ちょい
We'll give you everything we can.
あなたに全部あげるわ
だから 思い切り
やられてきてほしいの
So go out there and let them destroy you.
Fight once more
もう一度 戦って
so we can win.
勝つために！
（若松）バニシングドライブ！
（諏佐）抜いた!?
The Vanishing Drive!
He passed him?!
No!
（若松）いや 見えてる！
He sees him!
Kuroko can't come back if we
just take him off the court.
黒子を ただ引っ込めたら
それこそ再起不能だ
We need him to keep playing
だから あえて
プレーを続けてもらって—
so we can find a way to revive him together.
みんなで黒子の復活策を見つけ出す
黒子！
Kuroko...
うわっ これも見えてる
They can see that, too!
No, you don't!
させるか！
（火神）だあっ！
（葉山）あっ！
Rakuzan
Seirin
Rakuzan made a comeback!
（若松）ついに洛山が逆転！
どういうつもりか
知らないけど—
I don't know what you're thinking.
彼を入れたまま
ウチとやろうなんて—
But it's naive to think
you can beat us with him.
甘いんじゃない？
Rebound!
（伊月）リバンッ！
Damn!
（火神）しまった！
Yeah!
っしゃあ！
（根武谷）ぐわっ
（誠凛部員たち）
やったぁ バイスクロー
Yeah! Vice Claw!
Kiyoshi!
（日向）木吉！
（日向）さっきの…
What you just said...
ウチが甘いんじゃなくて
そっちがナメてんじゃね？
We're not naive. You're underestimating us.
ふーん
Rakuzan
Seirin
（リコ）第１クオーターを
同点で締めたのは上出来ね
Good job tying them after the first quarter.
But you're out again, Kuroko-kun.
でも 交代よ 黒子君
３分足らずで解決策を出すのは
さすがに無理だけど—
We couldn't come up with a
solution in three minutes,
but we got some information.
情報は取れたわ
復活の糸口を考えるためにも—
You're out during the second quarter
so we can come up with a plan.
第２クオーターは
一度下がって様子を見るわよ
（黒子）はい
Okay.
Cheer up, Kuroko.
元気出せよ 黒子！
勝つためには また
オマエのパスが必要なんだ
We'll need your passes again to win.
We can't go down without a fight.
うつむく前に 少しでも あがこうぜ
火神君
Kagami-kun...
We scraped through the first quarter
even while you were useless.
まったく使い物になんねぇオマエ
入れたままでも—
第１クオーター
なんとかなったんだ！
Don't worry about us.
こっちのことは心配すんな！
（黒子）分かっていますが—
I know, but couldn't you
sugarcoat it instead?
できればオブラートに包んで
言ってくれませんか
You're right, though.
でも そうですね
I'll return to the court.
絶対 もう一度
コートに戻ります
勝つために
To win.
おう
Yeah!
頼むぜ 黒子！
We're counting on you, Kuroko!
第２クオーターも勝算はある
We stand a chance in the second quarter.
They may be Rakuzan,
but they're not all monsters.
いくら洛山といっても—
５人全員化け物ってわけじゃない
Especially No. 5...
特に５番… 黛(まゆずみ)って選手は—
水戸部なら十分戦える相手だ
Even Mitobe can handle Mayuzumi easily.
We know Seirin's strength.
（白金）誠凛の力は十分 分かった
第２クオーターは
プランどおりで問題ない
We'll stick to the plan
in the second quarter.
いいな 赤司
Got it, Akashi?
Yes, sir.
はい ここから先は
蹂躙(じゅうりん)するのみ
All that's left is to destroy them.
小太郎 永吉 玲央
Kotaro, Eikichi, Leo.
You'll score.
点を取ってもらうぞ
I'll pass you the ball.
ボールを回す
We couldn't use it against
Shutoku's Hawk Eye user.
秀徳(しゅうとく)戦ではホークアイの使い手が
いたせいで使わなかったが—
それほど視野の広くない
イーグルアイならば—
But there's something we can
use against the limited range
使えるルートはある
of the Eagle Eye.
Satsuki, what's Rakuzan's No. 5 like?
（青峰）さつき
洛山の５番ってどんなヤツだ？
Huh? Give me a second.
え？ ちょっと待って
Let's see...
えっと…
黛 千尋(ちひろ) ３年 パワーフォワード
Mayuzumi Chihiro. Third-year. Power Forward.
Technique
Power
Speed
Mayuzumi Chihiro
Third-Year DF Height 182 cm Weight 69 kg
Mental Strength                          Offense                                Defense
Stamina
Flexibility
スピード パワー テクニック
そのほとんどがＣランク
His speed, power, and
technique are all rank C.
He has no particular strengths or weaknesses.
これといった 得意 不得意もなし
レギュラーになったのは３年
He became a regular in his third year,
赤司君が入って しばらくした頃
shortly after Akashi joined the team.
Before then, he wasn't
even on the first string.
それ以前はベンチどころか
１軍にも入っていなかった
（青峰）なんだそりゃ
Seriously? Sounds just like someone I know.
そっくりじゃねぇか
どっかの誰かとよ
What?
（伊月）赤司がパスミス？
Akashi failed his pass?
（木吉）取れる！
I got it!
What?!
（木吉）なに!?
Was that...
今のは…
Misdirection?!
ミスディレクション!?
You're joking...
うそ… だろ
まさか… 黒子と同じ？
Is he just like Kuroko?
少し違うな
He's a little different.
He is like Tetsuya, but his
fundamentals are all stronger.
彼はテツヤと同じ特性を
持ちながら—
基本性能は
すべて一回り高い
Tetsuya is the old model.
いわばテツヤは旧型
Mayuzumi Chihiro is the
new Phantom Sixth Man.
黛 千尋は
新型の幻のシックスマンだ
Preview
（葉山）ようやく出番か 黛さん！
It's finally your time
to shine, Mayuzumi-san!
（実渕）試合には
ずっと 出てたでしょう 一応
He was playing the whole time.
（根武谷）オレにいいパス
くれるなら それでいいぜ
Just keep the good passes headed my way.
Ei-chan, no fair!
（葉山）永(えい)ちゃん ずりぃ
I'll make a ton of shots, too!
オレだって
バンバン決めちゃうもんね
Miracles Don't Happen
（実渕）うっさいわよ あんたたち
Shut up, boys!